ALESSANDRO CONWAY

(412) 297-9959 | alessandro.conway@gmail.com

EDUCATION

Master of Research, Economics Sciences Po, Doctoral School Graduate training at Europe's leading economics and policy university	Aug. 2018 - Sep. 2020 Paris, France
Bachelor of Philosophy, Economics, International Studies University of Pittsburgh, Honors College 'Summa cum laude' with the highest undergraduate degree attainable	Aug. 2013 - Aug. 2017 Pittsburgh, USA
RELEVANT EXPERIENCE	
 Research Assistant Banque de France - Sciences Po. Supervisor: Dr. Paul Hubert Evaluated the effect of fiscal policy with a focus on wealth distribution Compiled and manipulated data in R, regression analysis using STATA 	May 2021 - Present Paris, France (remote)
 Master's Thesis Sciences Po. Supervisor: Dr. Xavier Ragot Wrote and defended a dissertation on wellbeing and macroeconomic policy Created a cutting-edge model in Julia, analyzed economic growth and equity 	Mar. 2020 - Sep. 2020 Paris, France
 Internship French Economic Observatory (O.F.C.E.). Supervisor: Dr. Eric Heyer Compiled a novel database in Excel for fiscal policy analysis of five large countries 	May 2019 - Aug. 2020 Paris, France

SKILLS

Research: quantitative analysis, impact evaluation, modeling, forecasting, innovative techniques *Topics* • Public Policy, Macroeconomics, Inequality, Labor Economics, Trade, Wellbeing *Methods* • Statistics and Probability, Econometrics, Numerical Methods

• Literature reviews and collaboration with external researchers to build upon expertise

Communication

Languages • English, Italian, French (native); Spanish (fluent); German (basic)

Public Audience • Two dissertations; five articles published as a Staff Writer for The Pitt News

Computing

Programming and Modeling • Julia, Python, MATLAB, Dynare
Data Analysis and Compilation • R, STATA, MS Excel; SQL
Data Visualization and Presentation • Julia, R, basic proficiency in QGIS; IATEX, LyX,
MS Word; MS PowerPoint, Beamer

HONORS AND AWARDS

Fulbright U.S. Student Grant, U.S. Department of State	2018
Certificate in Social Sciences and Humanities, Sciences Po	2017
Student-Honoree, University of Pittsburgh	2017
University Honors College Scholar, University of Pittsburgh	2017

PERSONAL STATEMENT

My personal background is unique: I am a US citizen with Italian and New Zealand parents and grew up in the US, France, and Italy. As a consequence, I am natively fluent in English, Italian and French (speaking, reading and writing). I have also picked up an equivalent fluency in Spanish frommy studies, and recently started on German. Through these experiences I have also developed a unique global perspective and an affinity with diversity.

My interest in individual wellbeing stems from seeing the disparate effects of the '08 financial crisis and the divergent paths of recovery, both economically and in terms of quality of life. I have a personal commitment to bettering wellbeing by developing a thorough understanding of the underlying dynamics upon which to base effective, unbiased, and sustainably impactful policy proposals. My studies have revealed some key notions:

- Economic policy and shocks are very influential for impacting people's behavior and livelihoods
- Socio-economic issues like wealth and racial inequality, educational and income inequality, and climate change are intersectional
- Personal wellbeing is multidimensional and economic factors can impact its components differently

These guide me as I seek to develop effective research-based policy through independent and collaborative work, public-private stakeholder engagement, consensus-building, and advocacy.

I welcome the opportunity to further discuss my qualifications and career ambitions.